University of Connecticut, President's Office Records [Harry J. Hartley, 1990-1997] 1999.0008
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
University of Connecticut, President's Office Records [Harry J. Hartley, 1990-1997]
undated, 1990-2000.
1999.0008
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
9.5 Linear feet
The collection contains administrative records associated with the tenure of Harry J. Hartley, President of the University of Connecticut from 1990-1997.
Hartley, Harry J.
University of Connecticut.
Scope and Content
The collection contains the transcript of an interview between Dr. Hartley and Dr. Bruce Stave of the Center for Oral History and published materials documenting Dr. Hartley's activities while serving as the President of the University of Connecticut. Dr. Hartley added a complete file on the history of UConn 2000 and a copy of the book he wrote concerning the planning, development and implementation of the $1 billion project in October 2001. Dr. Hartley donated these materials already ordered.
Arrangement
Series I: Oral History and related materials ( undated, 1990-1996 )
Series II: Editorials ( 1990-1996 )
Series III: Speeches ( undated, 1991-1996 )
Series IV: Inauguration( 1991 )
Series V: Oversize materials( undated )
Series VI: UConn 2000 ( 1994-2000 )
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
1995 Connecticut Legislative Guide. Office of Legislative Management. Hartford, CT: Office of Legislative Management, 1995. Dodd Call No.
Beyond 2000: Change; Strategic Plan for the University of Connecticut. University of Connecticut. Storrs, CT: University of Connecticut, 1995. Dodd Call No.
UConn 2000: Four Year Progress Report. University of Connecticut. Storrs, CT: University of Connecticut, 1999. Dodd Call No. C 5540
UConn 2000: Planning, Politicking, and Managing a Billion Dollar Campus Transformation. Hartley, Harry J. Storrs, CT: Harry J. Hartley, 2000. Dodd Call No. C 6607
Access
The collection is open and available for use.
Acquisition Information
Oral History materials transferred from the Center for Oral History in January 1999. Remaining materials transferred from the Office of the President. UConn 200 materials donated by Dr. Hartley in October 2001.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
College presidents—Connecticut.; University of Connecticut—Presidents—Interviews.; Archives.; Correspondence.; Educator; Interviews.; Personal Papers.; University of Connecticut.
- Series I: Oral History and related materials, undated, 1990-1996
  - Interview (1 of 2), 1996 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Interview (2 of 2), 1996 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Index to Interview, 1996 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Timeline of Administration UConn 2000, 1990-1996 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
    - Strategic Plan for the University of Connecticut, undated (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - Act, undated (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Publications
    - Connecticut Magazine “ About Harry” October, 1991 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
    - Hartford Courant “ Northeast” section, 1995 July 30 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
    - President Hartley's Five Year Report, 1990-1995 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
    - President Hartley's Annual Report, 1995-1996 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
    - Dodd Center Dedication, 1995 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - Emeritus Title, 1996 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
- Series II: Editorials, 1990-1996
  - Editorials, 1990-1992 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
  - Editorials, 1993-1996 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
- Series III: Speeches, undated, 1991-1996
  - Index, 1991-1993 (Box 2:, Folder 15)
  - Index, 1944-1996 (Box 2:, Folder 16)
  - Speeches, 1991 (Box 2:, Folder 17)
  - Speeches, 1992 (Box 2:, Folder 18)
  - Speeches, 1993 (Box 2:, Folder 19)
  - Speeches, 1994 (Box 2:, Folder 20)
  - Speeches, 1995 January - August (Box 2:, Folder 21)
  - Speeches, 1995 September - December (Box 2:, Folder 22)
  - Speeches, 1996 (Box 2:, Folder 23)
  - Canceled and General Remarks, undated, 1992 (Box 2:, Folder 24)
- Series IV: Inauguration Files, 1991
  - Invitations, Announcements, Flyers, 1991 (Box 2:, Folder 25)
  - Photographs, 1991 (Box 2:, Folder 26)
- Series V: Oversize, undated
  - Plaque (Box 3)
  - Flyers (Inauguration)
- Series VI: UConn 2000, undated, 1994-2000
  - Part One: Planning, undated (Box 4)
    - Capital Request to Trustees FY 1995-1997, 1994 (Box 4:, Folder 27)
    - “UConn 2000” Task Force Meetings and Minutes, 1994-1995 (Box 4:, Folder 28)
    - Election—Governor, 1994 (Box 4:, Folder 29)
    - University Senate Minutes, 1994 (Box 4:, Folder 30)
    - Trustees— Claire Leonardi, 1994 (Box 4:, Folder 31)
    - Board of Trustees Meeting Minutes, 1994 (Box 4:, Folder 32)
    - Friendly Related Articles, 1990-1991 (Box 4:, Folder 33)
    - “Fast-Track” Proposal (Prisons), 1991-1994 (Box 4:, Folder 34)
    - President's 5 year Report, 1995 (?) (Box 4:, Folder 35)
  - Part Two: Technical Data
    - Scope of UConn 2000, 1995 (Box 4:, Folder 36)
    - Dean's Outreach, 1995 (Box 4:, Folder 37)
    - Various Campus Organizations, 1995 (Box 4:, Folder 38)
    - Editorials—Articles, 1995 (Box 4:, Folder 39)
    - Testimony to the Legislature, 1995 (Box 4:, Folder 40)
    - Charts and Graphs (supporting testimony), 1995 (Box 4:, Folder 41)
    - Winning Elections, 1995 (Box 4:, Folder 42)
    - Capital Improvement, Authorization and Financing Program, Internal Group Discussion Draft, 1995 (Box 4:, Folder 43)
    - Section by section Outline of HB 6785, 1995 (Box 4:, Folder 44)
    - Attorney General concerns and response, 1995 (Box 4:, Folder 45)
    - Test of HB 6785 and Phase I Projects, 1995 (Box 4:, Folder 46)
  - Part Two: Political Phase
    - UConn 2000 Task Force Meetings and Minutes, 1995 (Box 4:, Folder 47)
    - Hartley Names Provost, 1994 (Box 4:, Folder 48)
    - Strategic Plan, 1995 (Box 4:, Folder 49)
    - Public Announcement, 1995 (Box 4:, Folder 50)
    - Meetings with Tom Ritter, 1995 (Box 4:, Folder 51)
    - “The Ritter Years” 1993-1998, undated (Box 4:, Folder 52)
    - Appropriations Committee, 1995 (Box 4:, Folder 53)
    - Economic Impact Analysis Report, 1995 (Box 4:, Folder 54)
    - Public Act 95-230, 1995 (Box 4:, Folder 55)
    - New Legislation requested by UConn, 1995 (Box 4:, Folder 56)
    - Board of Governors for Higher Education, FY 1995-1997 Budget (Box 4:, Folder 57)
  - Lobbying
    - Communications Plan—Mintz & Hoke, 1995 (Box 5:, Folder 58)
    - Focus Groups, 1995 (Box 5:, Folder 59)
    - Public Hearings, 1995 (Box 5:, Folder 60)
    - Newspaper Editorials campaign, 1995 (Box 5:, Folder 61)
    - Unions, 1995 (Box 5:, Folder 62)
    - Direct Mail campaign, 1995 (Box 5:, Folder 63)
    - Grass Roots mobilization, 1995 (Box 5:, Folder 64)
    - Letters from Legislators, 1995 (Box 5:, Folder 65)
    - Letters to Legislators, 1995 (Box 5:, Folder 66)
  - Testimony
    - Testimony, 1995 March 3 (Box 5:, Folder 67)
  - Part Two: Publications, mailings and brochures
    - Posters and flyers, 1995 (Box 5:, Folder 68)
    - General Obligation Bonds, 1995 (Box 5:, Folder 69)
    - Alumni Phones and Letters, 1995 (Box 5:, Folder 70)
    - Traditions, 1995 (Box 5:, Folder 71)
    - Stories, Editorials, Commentaries, Letters to the Editor, 1995 (Box 5:, Folder 72)
    - President's 5 year Report 1990-1995 (Box 6:, Folder 73)
    - Connecticut Magazine, 1991 (Box 6:, Folder 74)
    - Connecticut Alumnus, 1994 (Box 6:, Folder 75)
    - Northeast ( Hartford Courant Sunday Magazine), 1995 (Box 6:, Folder 76)
    - General Catalogues, 1994-1995 (Box 6:, Folder 77)
  - Part Three: Post UConn 2000
    - Enrollment, 2000 (Box 6:, Folder 78)
    - Neag Gift, 1999 (Box 6:, Folder 79)
    - Press Conferences, 1998-2000 (Box 6:, Folder 80)
    - Bond Sales, 1996 (Box 6:, Folder 81)
    - Testimony, 1995 (Box 6:, Folder 82)
    - Charts and Graphs (supporting testimony), 1995 (Box 6:, Folder 83)
    - “The Plan”, undated (Box 6:, Folder 84)
    - 52 Steps, undated (Box 6:, Folder 85)
    - Critics and Opponents to UConn 2000, 1995 (Box 6:, Folder 86)
    - Hartley as Interim Provost, 1994 (Box 6:, Folder 87)
    - Appendices for Part I (I, II, III), undated (Box 6:, Folder 88)
    - Key Players, undated (Box 6:, Folder 89)
    - Rebecca Lobo, 1995 (Box 6:, Folder 90)
    - Meetings and Minutes, 1994 (Box 6:, Folder 91)
    - Peter McFadden, 2000 (Box 6:, Folder 92)
- Series VII: 2007 Transfer
  - Files (Box 2007_A)
  - Files (Box 2007_B)
- Series VIII: 2010 Transfer
  - Files (Box 2010_1)
  - Files (Box 2010_2)
  - Files (Box 2010_3)